<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rust AV</title><link>https://rustav.org/</link><description>Recent content on Rust AV</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rustav.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rust-av: Rust and Multimedia</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/2018-02-18-rust-av-and-multimedia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/blog/2018-02-18-rust-av-and-multimedia/</guid><description>Rust-av: Rust and Multimedia Recently I presented my new project at Fosdem and since I was afraid of not having enough time for the questions I trimmed the content to the bare minimum. This blog post should add some more details.
What is it? Rust-av aims to be a complete multimedia toolkit written in rust.
Rust is a quite promising language that aims to offer high execution speed while granting a number of warranties on the code behavior that you cannot have in C, C++, Java and so on.</description></item><item><title>Using rav1e - from your own code</title><link>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-09-using-rav1e-from-your-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/blog/2019-04-09-using-rav1e-from-your-code/</guid><description>AV1, Rav1e, Crav1e, an intro AV1 is a modern video codec brought to you by an alliance of many different bigger and smaller players in the multimedia field. I&amp;rsquo;m part of the VideoLAN organization and I spent quite a bit of time on this codec lately.
rav1e: The safest and fastest AV1 encoder, built by many volunteers and Mozilla/Xiph developers. It is written in rust and strives to provide good speed, quality and stay maintainable.</description></item><item><title>Code Of Conduct</title><link>https://rustav.org/codeofconduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/codeofconduct/</guid><description>Scope Joining and participation agreement This document describes Rust-AV&amp;rsquo;s Code of Conduct for public communication mediums, who shall enforce said Code of Conduct, the action taken should the Code of Conduct be broken, as well as the method for appeals. Questions about this document and its contents can be directed to the org issue tracker.
This document is based on the Gentoo Code of Conduct
Important: By joining and/or participating in the Rust-AV community, you are stating that you accept and agree to adhere to the rules listed below, even if you do not explicitly state so.</description></item><item><title>The rust-av Community</title><link>https://rustav.org/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rustav.org/community/</guid><description>About Rust-av aims to be a complete multimedia toolkit written in rust.
Rust is a quite promising language that aims to offer high execution speed while granting a number of warranties on the code behavior that you cannot have in C, C++, Java and so on.
Its zero-cost abstraction feature coupled with the fact that the compiler actively prevents you from committing a large class of mistakes related to memory access seems a perfect match to implement a multimedia toolkit that is easy to use, fast enough and trustworthy.</description></item></channel></rss>